（忆往昔）
你们都清楚我们可能需要谁
You both know who we might need.
来帮忙应付黑暗
to help deal with the Darkness.
你是梅塔特隆 那个大名鼎鼎的梅塔特隆吗
You're Metatron? The Metatron?
我不是大天使 我是神的书记员
I'm not an archangel, I'm the scribe of God.
恰克·雪利
Chuck Shurley?
他是上帝的先知
He's a prophet of the Lord.
我不知道先知都是怎么选出来的
I don't know how prophets are chosen.
我才不想做什么先知
I don't want to be a prophet.
对 谁也不想
No, you don't at all.
- 显然我是上帝 - 你不是上帝
- Obviously, I'm a god. - You're not a god.
上帝
God?!
我希望我们能完成
I'm hoping that you and I can finish.
我几个月前开始进行的创作
what I started a few months ago.
时间之初时 你不是一个人
You weren't alone in the beginning.
你妹妹也在
Your sister was with you.
我是原初 也将会是终结
I was the beginning, and I will be the end.
我会成为唯一
I will be all that there is.
我们是紧密相连的
We're bonded.
你是释放了我的人
You're the one who set me free.
得先让路西法去对付阿玛拉
Our priority is to set Lucifer loose on Amara.
但要先把路西法从小卡身体里驱逐出去
After we exorcise Lucifer out of Cass.
然后把他放进新皮囊里
and put him into a new vessel.
没用 路西法对他的控制太强
Useless. Lucifer's hold on him is too strong.
大天使加上上帝之力 并不能打败上帝的妹妹
Archangel plus God power doesn't trump God's sister.
我觉得你和我得好好地长谈一次
I think you and I need to have a nice long chat.
如果阿玛拉抹去重启 就把什么都毁了
If Amara wipes the slate, everything is destroyed.
我和我搭档见识过这种情况 好吗
My partner and I have seen this before, okay?
韦斯 哈里斯警官是被浓雾里的东西感染了
Wes, Deputy Harris were infected by something in this fog.
护身符 它能感应到上帝的存在
The amulet … it burns hot in God's presence.
你就是因为这个才回来了 是吧
I mean, that's why you're back, right?
这不是她的故事
This isn't her story.
是我的
It's mine.
（如今）
这究竟是怎么回事
What the hell's going on here, exactly?
我很乐意说明情况
I'm happy to… fill in the blanks,
但或许我们该去个可以坐下来谈谈的地方
but maybe we should go somewhere where we could actually sit down.
我们不要跟你去任何地方
We're not going anywhere with you.
我们怎么知道你是真的恰克
Okay, how do we even know that you're really Chuck.
不是什么疯狂的咒语或是幻象
and not just some crazy spell or manifest…ation.
凯文
Kevin?
两位
Guys!
你们貌似压力很大
You're looking stressed.
尤其是你
Especially you.
没事的
I-It's cool.
相信恰克吧
Trust Chuck.
不管他需要你们做什么
Whatever it is he needs you to do,
他肯定是觉得你们做得到
he must think you can handle it.
我一直信任你
I always trusted you.
是啊 结果多好
Yeah, that ended well.
你怎么…
How did you …
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好 考虑到全部情况吧
Yeah, I mean, you know, given the circumstances.
无意打扰
Yeah, I don't mean to interrupt.
但事情还挺多的呢
Kind of a plateful here.
凯文
And, Kevin…
你死了很久了
you've been in the Veil long enough.
你该升级了
It's time you had an upgrade.
我去
Holy crap.
[邪恶力量 第11季第21集]
好吧
Okay.
那么 恰克
So, wow, um, Chuck …
看来我们不能那么喊你 是吧
Well, I guess we don't call you that, huh?
这样更好
I prefer it.
好吧 那就是「恰克」了
Okay, uh, "Chuck" it is.
抱歉 你得
I'm sorry. You're gonna have to, uh,
给我和迪恩点时间消化
give Dean and me a moment to start to process.
我们都不知道你还在
We didn't even know you were around.
我们知道恰克 但我们不知道
I mean, we knew about Chuck, but we just didn't know about…
是你
Chuck.
我一直希望你是在的
I mean, I-I-I was hoping you were around.
我祈祷了 不知道你是不是
I-I-I prayed and I … but I don't know if they got, uh,
- 埋在垃圾邮件里了 - 萨姆
- lost in the spam or if - Sam?
- 嗯 - 话太多了
- Yeah? - Babbling.
好吧
Okay.
我明白不是每个人都觉得满意
I'm getting that not everyone's totally on board.
问题是 恰克
Here's the thing, um…Chuck…
无意冒犯
And I mean no disrespect.
我猜你回来是为了帮忙黑暗的事
I'm guessing you came back to help with the Darkness,
那很好
and that's great.
简直太好了
That's, you know … It's fantastic.
但你走了
Um, but you've been gone a … a…
很久了
long, long time.
这几千年来
And there's so much crap.
地球上发生了
that has gone down on the Earth.
好多破事
for thousands of years.
瘟疫 战争 屠杀
I mean, plagues and wars, slaughters.
你一直在…写书吗
And you were, I don't know, writing books,
参加粉丝大会
going to fan conventions.
你知道外面都发生什么了吗 还是把那些屏蔽了
Were you even aware, o-or did you just tune it out?
我知道 迪恩
I was aware, Dean.
但你什么都没做
But you did nothing.
再说一次 我不是想惹你生气
And, again, I-I'm not trying to piss you off.
我可不想变成枕头或者盐
You know, I don't want to turn into a pillar of salt.
其实 那个不是我干的
I actually … I didn't do that.
好吧
Okay.
人们都对你祈祷
People … People pray to you.
人们为你建教堂
People build churches for you.
为你发起战争 你却什么都没做
They fight wars in your name, and you did nothing.
你不爽
You're frustrated.
我理解
I get it.
相信我 我原本亲力亲为
Believe me, I was hands-on …
真的
Real hands-on for,
做了好久
wow, ages.
我以为 如果我一直插手
I was so sure if I kept stepping in,
教导 惩罚
teaching, punishing,
这些我创造的美妙生灵
that these beautiful creatures that I created…
就会长大
would grow up.
但他们却没变化
But it only stayed the same.
我明白我必须离开
And I saw that I needed to step away.
让我的宝宝自己找到路
and let my baby find its way.
过度干涉已经不是为父之道了
Being overinvolved is no longer parenting.
而是要把控制权交给他们
It's enabling.
但情况并没好转
But it didn't get better.
我一直在考虑
Well, I've been mulling it over.
就我看来 我觉得是变好了
And from where I sit, I think it has.
就我看来 像是你抛弃了我们
Well, from where I sit, it feels like you left us.
然后给自己找借口
and you're trying to justify it.
我知道你小时候过得不容易 迪恩
I know you had a complicated upbringing, Dean,
但别把我当成你爸爸了
but don't confuse me with your dad.
结束你的痛苦吧 路西法
End your suffering, Lucifer.
召唤他出来 求他救你
Call out to him. Beg him to save you.
你要我求爸爸来救他的完蛋儿子吗
Want me to beg daddy to come rescue his screw-up of a son?
我不怎么喜欢老爸
I'm no fan of Pops,
但他的确创造了
but he did make all of…
一切
you know, everything.
而这是你永远做不到的
And that's something that you could never do,
因为你一直以来只想要虚无
because all you ever wanted was nothing.
这不怎么激励人 是吧
It's not too inspiring, is it?
你很厉害 阿玛拉
You're strong, Amara.
你或许能击败他
You may defeat him.
但你永远成不了他
But you will never be him.
你得明白黑暗的这一点
You have to understand this about the Darkness …
她很无情
she's relentless,
是一股人类无法理解的力量
a force beyond human comprehension.
所以我才出现了
It's the only reason I came off the sidelines.
做她哥哥感觉很棒吧
Must have been great being her brother, huh?
最糟糕了
It was the worst.
总对我指手画脚 要我按她说的做
Always telling me what to do, making me do what she wanted.
你们理解的
I mean, you guys know how that works.
她在哪
So, where is she?
不知道 两位
No freakin' idea, fellas.
她对自己做了防护 让我找不到
She's warded herself specifically against me.
你们查到什么了
What have you come up with?
没有 我们都查了几个月了
Zip, and we've been at it for months.
迟早的
Well…matter of time.
我一直相信你们
I've always had faith in you…
即便你们不相信我
…even if you didn't return the favor.
客房在哪
Where's the guest room?
我需要洗个澡
I could use a shower.
在
Uh, it's, um…
沿走廊 左边第四扇门
just down the hallway … the fourth door on the left.
恰克
Hey, Chuck.
你知道她抓了路西法吧
You know that she's got Lucifer, right?
据我们听说
The way we heard it, um…
你上次把黑暗关起来时
last time when you bottled up the Darkness,
不是凭你一人之力
it … it took more than just you.
据说路西法也帮忙了
I mean, we heard that Lucifer was involved.
不
No.
不吗
No?
路西法或许曾是我最大的期望
Lucifer was perhaps my greatest hope.
也是我最深的失望
and my bitterest disappointment.
你觉得如果我能信任他
Do you think if I could have trusted him for a moment,
还会把他关进笼子吗
I would have put him in the Cage?
我本不想提的
And I wasn't gonna mention this,
但是多谢你们把他弄出来了
but thank you so much for springing him.
并不是计划好的
That wasn't really the plan, um…
他之前虽然糟糕 但关了那么久的监狱
Now, as bad as he was, after all this time in prison,
现在大概更糟了
he's probably worse.
现在 他或许已跟阿玛拉成了盟友
And by now, he could have formed an alliance with Amara.
别去闯陷阱 伙计们
Not walking into that trap, guys.
所以 不行
So, no.
主如是说
Thus spake the Lord.
外面有什么东西
Something's out there.
一直有的
Hmm, always is.
这个是新的 有什么变了
This is new. Something's changed.
或许老爸注意到了你最近的疯狂屠杀
Maybe Dad picked up ‭on your latest slaughterfest.
宠坏的熊孩子
Spoiled brat.
我需要安宁 他却想要粉丝俱乐部
I needed solitude ‭and he needed a fan club,
于是他创造了那堆东西
so he made all that.
我一抱怨
Then when I complained,
他就跟你一起把我塞进一个洞里 关了那么久
he stuffed me in a hole for eons … with your help.
别抱怨了
Stop whining.
我不需要听你责备
I don't need this.
拜托 阿玛拉 你在哪
Come on, Amara. Where are you?
我想你了 迪恩
I've missed you, Dean.
我们好久没说话了
It's been a while since we've spoken.
我知道我哥哥出现了
I'm aware my brother has surfaced.
如果你们碰到了 如果他来找你了
If you should cross paths, if he should reach out to you,
告诉他
he should know this …
路西法 他的宠儿 现在状况不太好
Lucifer, his favorite, isn't doing so well.
更别提那具皮囊 你的朋友卡西迪奥了
Say nothing of the vessel, your friend Castiel.
我哥哥无视我
By choosing to ignore me,
就是在纵容这事
my brother is allowing this to happen.
还有其他事
These and… other things.
你该知道
I thought you should know.
（俄克拉荷马州 刘易斯）
有发现吗
Anything?
没有
Nada.
- 嗯 谢谢 - 没事
- Yeah, thanks. - Yeah.
真不敢相信我会这么说
You know, I can't believe I'm gonna say this,
但我这次真希望罗威娜在
but, for once, I actually wish Rowena was here.
或许她能找到阿玛拉
I mean, maybe she could track down Amara.
她以前就成功过
She's done it before.
是啊 但可以打赌 她和《诅咒之书》会
Yeah, but you can bet she and the Book are gonna stay stashed.
一直躲到事情平息
until this whole thing is over.
恰克呢
Where's Chuck?
睡懒觉吧
Sleeping in, I guess.
上帝还睡觉吗
Does God sleep?
我知道他洗澡的时间特别长
I know he takes really long showers.
是吧 还唱歌 难听的老民歌
Right, and sings, too … like, crappy old folk songs.
我三次叫他消停点
I had to tell him to cool it three times.
你叫上帝消停点
You told God to cool it?
是啊 我还要睡觉呢
Yeah, I sleep.
我知道现在情况很奇怪
You know, I know this is a really strange situation and all,
但也挺有意思的 是吧
but it's also really amazing, you know?
这可是上帝
I mean, it's God.
我有好多话想问他
There's so many things I want to ask him,
比如 星球
uh, like, uh, t-the planets, you know?
为什么是圆的
Why are they round?
还有耳朵 我一直觉得耳朵很奇怪
Or ears. I always thought they were strange.
行了 迷弟 冷静
Okay, fanboy, calm down.
我们集中精神
Let's stay focused.
我们得赶紧找到路西法 否则要来不及了
We got to find Lucifer before it's too late.
来不及
Too late?
阿玛拉 她进入了我的头脑
Amara is … she's in my head.
我也不想的 她突然就出现了
Hey, I didn't ask for it, okay? She just showed up.
她让我看到了路西法
But she's showing me visions of … of Lucifer.
就是小卡 他的样子糟透了
By Lucifer, I mean Cass, and he looks like crap …
看来她对他真的伤得不轻
like she's really doing a number on him.
早啊
Morning.
那是我的睡袍吗
Is that my robe?
听我的
I'm telling you guys,
跟路西法搅到一起是个错误
it's a mistake to get mixed up with Lucifer.
虽然我也很痛苦 但我不得不离开他
Much as it pained me, I had to walk away.
太闹腾了
Too much drama.
你们有培根吗
Do you have any bacon?
你吃培根
You eat bacon?
- 是啊 - 两位 新情况
- Yeah. - Hey, guys, this just came up.
看来阿玛拉迷雾
Looks like that fog, the, um… Amara fog,
又侵袭了一座小镇
uh, hit another town.
怎么样
And?
这座小镇不像上一座那么幸运
And this one wasn't as lucky as the last one.
数千人死亡 每个人都死了
Thousands died. Uh, everybody died.
除了一个人
But, uh, except for one man.
你怎么没发现
How'd you miss that one?
她想诱我出来
She's baiting me.
我不能次次都回应
I can't respond every time.
我不要受她摆布
I won't be manipulated.
但死了数千人啊
Yeah, but thousands of people are dead.
很不幸
Unfortunately.
找到她吧
So find her.
我们为您带来关于
We have breaking news at this hour.
最近一起怪异天气事件的报道
on the most recent freak weather event.
州警现在证实一股神秘毒雾
State police are now confirming that a mysterious toxic fog.
昨晚笼罩了俄克拉荷马州刘易斯镇
engulfed the town of Lewis, Oklahoma, late last night.
据报 有大量人员死亡
Reports are also confirmed there were mass fatalities.
这起毒雾事件跟几天前
Descriptions of the event are identical to those.
遭遇毒雾侵袭的另一座小镇的情况相同
of the fog that overwhelmed another town in the days …
（神秘毒雾再次袭来 俄克拉荷马州刘易斯被毒雾笼罩）
（书记员来电）
干什么
What?
我发现你们跟恰克有接触
I notice you've been in touched with Chuck.
我有
Well, I've got some…
你们需要知道情报
information you're gonna need to know.
好啊 说吧
Okay, say it.
不行
No.
得当面说 我得带你们去看
It's got to be in person … something I got to show you.
拉德费尔德教授 我们是联调局
Professor Redfield. FBI.
- 叫我多纳泰罗就好 - 嗯
- Call me Donatello. - Yeah.
这名字是随他
I'm named after him.
忍者神龟吗
The Mutant Ninja Turtle?
文艺复兴时期的雕刻家
The, uh, Renaissance sculptor.
嗯 当然
Right, of course.
警察当我是恐怖分子
The cops think I'm a terrorist.
我在大学教化学
I-I teach chemistry at the university.
我的生活很宁静 还养了猫
I-I lead a quiet life. I have a cat!
现在没了
Had a cat.
我们对此深表遗憾
Well, we are, uh, sorry for your loss.
我们想问几个问题
Just a few questions.
除了毒雾 你那晚还发现
Um, other than the fog, did you notice anything or anyone.
街上有什么异常的情况或人吗
that seemed out of place on the street that night?
一切发生的好快
It … It all happened so fast.
我
I, uh…
那雾简直像无端冒出来的
It was like it came out of nowhere.
我们很少有雾 而且从没有那样的
We hardly ever get fog, and never like that.
太可怕了
It was horrible.
他们都掐着喉咙
They were clutching their throats.
就好像喘不过气
like … like … like they were choking.
然后
And…
他们的身体 天呐
Their bodies … Oh, my God …
显现出骇人的黑色条纹
these terrible black streaks.
然后就发生了
And that's when it happened.
那是我从没体验过的感觉
It was like nothing I've ever felt before in my life.
就好像我的头要爆炸了 但不是因为疼
It was like my head was exploding, only not with pain …
而是因为大量的知识 看清了很多事
with … with … with knowledge and … and clarity!
以前我根本不知道的事
Things that I'd never known before.
符号 声音 我根本不会的语言
Symbols and … and voices … in languages I don't speak!
然后
Then…
可怕
horrible…
非常可怕的幻象
horrible visions…
那是毁灭
of destruction…
和死亡
and death.
你们觉得我疯了
You think I'm crazy.
不 完全没有
No, uh, not at all.
能让我们单独谈谈吗
Just, uh, you know, will you give us a moment?
你发现这听起来很耳熟吧
I mean, you get that this is all sounding familiar, right?
是啊 就像凯文发现自己是先知的时候
Yeah. Yeah, like when Kevin found out he was a prophet.
那么这人是个先知吗
So, what, this guy's a prophet?
但克劳力之前不是把
Yeah, but I thought Crowley rounded up.
所有的潜在先知都抓起来想杀掉吗
all the future prophets and tried to kill them.
但我们救了他们
Yeah, but we rescued them.
多纳泰罗当时可不在
and Donatello wasn't a part of that,
但是啊 克劳力有可能漏了几个
but, yeah, it's possible Crowley missed a few.
显然 他并不知道自己排在凯文之后
And, obviously, he had no idea he was next in line after Kevin.
怎么能知道 他当时还没被上帝之力击中呢
How would he? He hadn't gotten hit by the God power yet.
阿玛拉的迷雾
So, Amara's fog …
那会不会是阿玛拉的神力
could it have been Amara's God power?
那也还是神力
It's still God power.
好吧 我得来杯咖啡
All right, I need a coffee.
嗯
Yeah.
我被捕了吗
Am … am I under arrest?
没有
No, just, um…
就是想再核实一下你的说法
want to check out a few more aspects of your story.
好了 你看下这个
Here we go. Would you look at this?
尽量去解读一下
Try and read it a little.
我读不懂
Oh, I can't. I …
我对此毫无了解
I don't know anything about it.
「请看上帝」
"Behold the face of God""
我一下就想到了
That came right to me.
- 这是谁的语言 - 天使
- Who speaks this language? - Angels.
我得见你 迪恩
I need to see you, Dean.
事情发生得很快 一切都会改变
Events are moving swiftly and everything will change.
我得跟你见面 但不能这样见
I need to meet with you, but not like this.
单独见
Somewhere alone.
我不可能是先知 我是无神论者 化学家
I can't b'ta prophet. I'm an atheist and a chemist!
我相信分子 不是上帝
I-I believe in molecules, not God.
好吧 按说先知
All right, well, we're pretty sure that prophets.
都是不知情的
don't even know they're in the game.
直到他们被上帝点化
until they've actually been touched by God, so…
上帝点化了我
I-I was touched by God?
或许是他妹妹 阿玛拉
Or possibly his sister, Amara.
- 他还有家人啊 - 是啊
- He has family? - Yeah.
她想干掉他 好毁灭宇宙
She wants him gone so she can annihilate the universe.
- 大致是如此 - 什么
- That's the headline. - What?
鉴于你可能与她有直接的联系
And since you might have a hotline to her,
我们希望你能帮我们找到她
we're hoping you can help us find her.
你们为什么要找到她
W-Why would you want to find her?
我们得救一个被她扣押的人
We got to rescue this guy she's holding.
- 是谁 - 路西法
- Who is? - Lucifer.
她侄子
Her nephew.
- 他目前附身了一个天使 - 对
- Who's possessing an angel at the moment. - ‭Yeah.
锁着呢
It's locked.
那边也是
Yeah, that, too.
有时候我们会把妖怪放在车后座
Sometimes we keep monsters in the back.
我做不到
I … I … I can't do this!
- 你行的 - 我真的不行
- Yeah, you can. - No, I promise you I can't.
我们不能逼你 你得自己想做
Look, we can't force you to do this. You've got to want this.
这就像让我相信圣诞老人
It … It's like asking me to believe in Santa Claus.
- 其实… - 迪恩 不是时候
- Oh, well, actually … - Dean, not now.
好吧 我们不求你相信这是真的
Okay, look, we … we're not asking you to believe that this is true,
装装样子就行
just act like you do.
人们成天装相
People do it all the time.
- 怎么了 - 我不知道
- What? - I … I-I don't know.
我好像感觉到了什么
I … I think I'm sensing something.
强大的存在
Something big.
阿玛拉吗
Like Amara?
好像不是
I don't think so.
但我怎么可能知道呢
Although, how would I know?
可能是
Could it be…
他
Him?
恰克
Hey, Chuck.
我们找到个人
We, uh, found someone.
他好像是下一位先知
I think he's the next prophet.
好诶
Neat-o.
那是我的电脑吗
Is that my computer?
我从没见过那么多黄片
I've never seen so much porn.
至少没一次性见过那么多
Not in one sitting.
我要…
It's … I'm gonna…
听着
So, uh, listen.
他对这神神鬼鬼的
He … He's … He's a little nutted out.
状况有点抓狂
about the whole booga-booga of it all,
或许别拿上帝什么的吓他了
so maybe just dial back the … the God stuff.
没穿裤子
No pants on.
- 萨姆 - 嗯
- Sam? - Yeah?
嗯
Yeah.
你安全了 走吧
All right, you're safe. Come on.
多纳泰罗 见到你很高兴
Donatello, good to see ya.
你猫的事我很遗憾
Sorry about your cat.
你认识我
You … You know me?
我创造了你
I made you.
我创造了你们所有人 包括那些尚未出世的人
I made all of you, even the ones who aren't born yet.
我的上帝
Oh, my God.
是你
It's you.
见到你很高兴 阁下
G-Good to meet you, Sir!
伟大神明殿下
Your … Your celestial magnificence, your …
行了
Hey, hey, hey, it's okay.
喊他恰克就行
He … He just kind of goes by Chuck.
可以了吧 你加入吧
So, we good? Y'all signed up?
我猜你知道我本是个无神论者
I-I-I guess you know that I was an atheist,
直到10分钟前
until 10 minutes ago.
这是个问题吗
Is that an issue?
我不介意 我相信我
Not for me. ‭I mean, I believe in me.
但你的怀疑是预料之中的
But your skepticism is to be expected.
毕竟我还给了人自由意志
I did include free will in the kit.
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard.
老板 来点玛格丽塔酒
Oh, uh, barkeep, dos margaritas!
拿最棒的龙舌兰给我的朋友
Top-shelf tequila please for my amigos.
他们请客
Their treat.
好了
All right.
我们来了 别耍花样
We're here. ‭Don't try to pull any crap.
我能耍什么花样
And what variety of crap could I possibly pull?
我已经没有能量了
I've lost my grace.
看我啊 我什么都没有
Look at me. I got nothing.
好吧 你为什么非要见我们
Okay, why did you have to see us?
什么事那么急
What's so urgent?
我发现你们见到了恰克
So, I, uh, notice you've been in touch with Chuck.
也就是那个谁
A.K.A., you know who.
嗯 你有什么话想说吗
Yeah, yeah. Is this going anywhere?
是的 恰克同意对付阿玛拉了
Yes, Chuck agreed to take on Amara.
他说的吗
He said that?
- 这是他原话吗 - 差不多
- Used those words? - Pretty much.
怎么 他不打算对付阿玛拉吗
So, what … ‭he's not confronting Amara?
不不
Oh, no. No, no, no.
他的确是要去见她
He's … He's going to … He's gonna…meet with her.
但他不会干掉她
He's just not gonna take her down.
他要
He's gonna…
牺牲自我
sacrifice himself.
任凭她处置
Let her do whatever she wants with him.
你真指望我们相信吗
Do you really expect us to buy this?
不
No.
当然不了
Of course not.
给
Here.
信这个吧
Buy this.
别管错别字 但好好读读
Ignore the typos, but read it.
都是他自己的原话
It's in his own words.
这不是自传
It's not an autobiography.
是遗书
It's a suicide note.
（上帝 一本自传）
你想谈
You wanted to talk.
这里似乎就不错
This seemed as good a place as any.
看他们 多么乐观
Look at them … endlessly optimistic.
风吹倒他的塔楼 他就重建
The wind blows over his tower, he rebuilds.
总能触动我
Always gets me.
如果是这样 你为什么要放弃
If that's so, why are you bailing?
你见到阿玛拉时 就要投降吗
When you see Amara, you're throwing in the towel?
梅塔特隆
Metatron.
大嘴巴
Loose lips.
但你觉得我是混蛋呢 你在乎个什么劲
But you think I'm a dick. Why do you care?
因为你失踪之前
Because before you went M.I.A…
做了很多事
you did a lot.
谢谢
Thank you.
你所谓的投降
And what you call throwing in the towel,
在我看来是策略
I call strategy.
被你妹妹杀死怎么能叫策略
How is death by your sister a strategy?
我了解她
I know her.
她是跟我有仇
Her beef is with me.
是啊 但我还是不明白 死
Yeah, but I still don't understand how … how dying.
怎么能塑造成功
is a … ‭a blueprint for success.
我不会死
I don't be dying.
我会被囚禁
I'll be caged.
我拿自己换我创造的一切
I trade myself for… everything I created.
世界得以延续
It goes on.
好吧
Okay, well, the, um,
我认识的那个阿玛拉
Amara that I know is…
充满了愤怒
a mountain of … of pissed off.
她一个人被关了那么久
I mean, she spent a … a gazillion years in solitary.
她唯一的想法就是 现在轮到她了
The only thing she's thinking is … is it's her turn.
我会给她机会 只要她接受交易
And I'll give it to her, as long as she accepts the deal.
交易 什么
The deal? What…
她会毁灭你的
She's gonna eliminate you,
然后她会毁掉你创造的一切
and then she's gonna destroy everything that you've created.
这是她亲口跟我说的
She's told me this personally.
这一切是你创造的
You started this.
全部是你创造的
You started all of this,
那么你就有权终结它吗
but does that give you the right to end it?
我们不是你可以随手丢掉的玩具
You know, we're not just some toys you throw away.
我觉得你欠我们更多
I think you owe us more than that.
如果我的计划不成功
If my plan doesn't work,
那人类就会站出来
then humans will step up.
你 萨姆
You, Sam,
其他天选者 得找到办法
others that are the chosen will have to find a way.
这就是我那么多年前救了你的原因
It's why I saved you years ago.
你是光明和黑暗之间的防火墙
You're the firewall ‭between light and darkness.
不
No.
不 我
No, I…
听着 吸血鬼 我对付得了
Look, give me a … a vampire, and I'm good.
但是 上帝的妹妹
But this … God's sister?
这太超出我的能力了
That is way above my pay grade.
我
I…
这
It…
总之 是你该来干掉她
Bottom line is i-it's you who has to take her out.
之后
And look, and then after that,
你是去坎昆买间公寓
you know, get a condo in Cancun.
我也不管
I don't care!
我给你拿了瓶啤酒 不知道你喝不喝
I got you a beer. ‭I don't know if you drink.
我现在喝了
I do now.
好了
Well…
我不知道恰克是不是会站在我们这边
I don't know… ‭If Chuck is leaning our way.
你不知道
You don't know?
如果我们真把路西法弄来一起帮忙
If we do get Lucifer for the added muscle,
那他或许会配合
then…maybe he'll play ball.
他们不是敌视彼此吗
I thought they hated each other.
是啊
Yeah, they do.
我真怀念做个无神论者
I so miss being an atheist.
好了 梅塔特隆 快说
All right, Metatron. Make it quick.
什么都别碰
Don't touch anything.
好吧
Fine.
迪恩
Dean!
多谢请我来
Thanks for inviting me.
请你
Inviting you?
你一晚上都在地堡外面转悠
You've been circling the building all night.
给我发了两百条傻逼符号表情的短信
You sent me 200 text messages with dumbass emojis.
给你三分钟
You got three minutes.
多纳泰罗
Donatello!
见到你很高兴
Pleasure to meet you.
梅塔特隆 我是上帝的书记员
Metatron, scribe of God.
你被设计出来时我就在
I was there when you were designed.
我把你的名字写在了天使眼皮内侧
I wrote your name on the inside of the angels' eyelids.
他要吓尿我了
He's freaking me out.
好了 你说想帮忙的
Okay. ‭You said you wanted to help.
除了世界级二逼 你还有什么能提供的
Besides world-class douchery, what do you have to offer?
没什么
Oh, nothing.
我不过是抄录了天使石碑 知道所有的咒语
I just transcribed the angel tablet and know all the spells.
我了解阿玛拉的心思
And I know what makes Amara tick.
我跟大老板认识很久很久了
And I had a relationship with the big guy for eons.
还要继续说吗
Shall I keep going?
那是我的
That's mine!
虽然我不愿承认
As much as I hate to admit this…
但他说的有道理
he kind of has a point.
是吗
I don't know.
你需要一切的帮助 哪怕是二逼的帮助
You need all the help you can get … even douche help.
你什么时候站在上帝这边了
And since when did you jump on the God wagon?
你以前根本不在乎啊
You never used to give a damn.
我曾经是不在乎
Well, I didn't … at one time.
现在他视死如归了 要把我们留给黑暗
Now that he's gone all kamikaze, leaving us with the Darkness,
我
I…
我自创世之初就在他身旁
I was by his side since the creation.
他相信我
He believed in me.
如果我能帮忙拯救他
If there's something I can do to help save him.
和他的创造 那么
and his creation, then…
我似乎就该那么做
…uh, it seems like I should.
我们计划把路西法从阿玛拉那儿救走
The plan is to rescue Lucifer from Amara.
然后让他把我们从阿玛拉的藏身处瞬移出来
Then he teleports us out of Amara's hideout.
然后我们说服恰克和他一起去打她
and we convince Chuck to use him to fight her.
这就是你们的计划
That's your plan?
你知道阿玛拉在哪吗
Do you even know where Amara is?
我可能知道她在哪
Um, I think I might know where she is.
我一直有种感应
I've been getting this vibe.
就好像我大脑皮层里有一股电脉冲
Uh, it's like a ping in my cerebral cortex.
那么可能是阿玛拉 也可能是中风
Oh, so either Amara or a stroke.
我们要怎么拖住阿玛拉 然后去
And how are we supposed to keep Amara busy while we're…
解救路西法
liberating Lucifer?
多谢联系我 迪恩
Thank you for reaching out to me, Dean.
你说你想见面
You said you wanted to meet.
我想你了
I missed you.
和你给我的感觉
And the… sensations you arouse.
我知道你也有同样的感觉
I know you feel the same way.
那么 我们怎么办
So…what do we do?
我们是不可能的
There can be no us.
我们该各自走开
We should just walk away.
那你为什么不走呢
Then why don't you?
天呐
Oh, goody.
三个臭皮匠啊
Larry, Curly, Moe.
搜寻营救
Search and rescue?
是老爸最喜欢的之一
It's one of Dad's favorites.
终于到你了
Your ticket finally got punched, huh?
很奇怪吧
It's wacky, isn't it?
前一秒 你还谁都不是
One minute, you're…nobody.
然后 你一下就变成圣女贞德了
And then … Shazam … you're Joan of Arc.
希望这次的结局能更好点
Let's, uh … Let's hope this ends better than that.
好了 寒暄够了
All right, can the small talk.
我们要救你出去
We're busting you out of here.
应该的
Well, it seems fair.
都是你们几个疯子
since I wouldn't be here if you lunatics.
设的局才害我被阿玛拉抓走
hadn't set me up to be grabbed by Amara.
你得帮我们干掉她
You're gonna help us take her down.
如果你拒绝 我们就把你丢在这儿
If you say no, we'll just leave you here in Abu Ghraib.
拒绝
Say no?
你看到她对我做了什么吗
You see what she's done to me?
你觉得我喜欢她吗
Do I look like a fan?!
这地方 这世界
This place, this world.
让你过得不怎么容易
hasn't been especially easy for you.
为什么不至少考虑下我的提议
Why not at least consider my offer?
这世界的确不完美 我承认
This world is flawed. I will give you that.
但我还没准备好跟它告别
But I am not ready to say goodbye to it just yet.
但不管怎样 你都得跟它道别
But one way or the other, you will.
这是不可避免的
It's inevitable.
我哥哥别想再次阻止我
My brother won't stop me again,
他做不到
because he can't.
迪恩 放弃你的渺小
Dean, give up your… smallness,
你的人性吧 加入我 成为无限
your humanity and become boundless within me.
[咒语]
你从速记员群里把他揪出来的吗
Did you grabbed this from the steno pool?
你明白你要跟你父亲一起联手吧
You understand you'll be working with your father.
这是个问题吗
Is that gonna be a problem?
那是家仇
That's family.
这事更重要
This is bigger.
你会暂且搁置以前的宿怨
So, you'll table all the old stuff?
天堂的麻烦都留在天堂
What happens in Heaven stays in Heaven.
[咒语]
梅塔特隆 怎么样了
Metatron, are we getting any closer?
迪恩不能一直拖下去
Dean can't stall forever.
我在筛选
I'm … I'm … I'm narrowing it down.
你说得对 我是受你吸引
You're right. I am drawn to you.
这让我很烦恼
And it bothers the hell out of me,
因为我不能自控
'cause I can't control it.
那何必抵抗
Then why fight it?
你的感觉
What you're feeling.
是我是你挣扎的终结
is that I am the end of your struggle.
有什么阻止了你
Something stops you.
让你不能得到一切
Keeps you from having it all.
[咒语]
太好了
Yes.
你在想什么
Where are your thoughts?
有什么变了
Something's different.
路西法 快把我们瞬移出去
Hey, Lucifer, zap us out of here … quick!
不行啊
Oh, no can do.
什么意思
What do you mean you can't do it?
暂时禁足了
Temporarily grounded.
设备故障
Equipment malfunction.
你跟上帝说过话
You've spoken with God.
你见过他了
You've seen him.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
各位 我能感觉到她了
Guys, I'm … I'm feeling her!
她要来了
She's coming!
好吧 我们快走 好了
All right, we're out of here. Okay.
来
Come on.
好了 梅塔特隆 快走
All right, Metatron, come on.
没事 萨姆 你走吧
It's okay, Sam. You go.
什么 走啊
What?! Come on!
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我来应付她
I got this.
书记员
The secretary.
你那是在开玩笑吧
You were kidding with that, weren't you?
他是好意
He meant well.
别毁了宇宙
Spare the universe.
省省吧
Spare this.
你们不值得我放过
You really aren't worth sparing.
你们都不配
None of you.
怎么回事
What happened?!
我们在哪
Where are we?
家
Home.
我偶尔是会回应祈祷的
Occasionally, I do answer a prayer.
你变了
You've changed.
你也变了
其实…
Well, still…
我没怎么变
I'm really pretty much the same.
还觉得紧张 是吗
Still twitchy, huh?
你见过了上帝 路西法 黑暗
Well, you met God, Lucifer, and the Darkness.
你得去水疗好好泡一天
You're gonna need a spa day.
要么就找一对儿妓女
That or a pair of hookers.
我得去理清思路
Ah, I have to sort it all out,
看看接下来做什么
see what comes next.
我不太想回归学术界
I don't feel much like returning to academia,
更不能再做回无神论者了
and I sure as hell can't go back to being an atheist.
是啊 我理解
Yeah, I hear ya.
谢谢…吧
Thank you…I guess.
如果
And, uh…
真有明天 鉴于你们的工作
if there is a tomorrow, given your line of work,
我们大概还会再见
I'll probably see you again.
别消失 我们或许还用得上你
Stay tuned. We may need you.
梅塔特隆为大家牺牲了
So, Metatron took one for the team.
- 是啊 - 真是没想到
- Yeah. - ‭Well, I wouldn't have called that.
你想跟我说说吗
So, you want to tell me about it?
阿玛拉显然是察觉到不对劲
I mean, Amara obviously figured out something was going on,
但她没杀了你
and she didn't rip your head off.
她要我成为她的一部分
She wants me to be a part of her.
不是隐喻 是真的合体
Not metaphorically, I'm talking literally …
永远合体
forever.
也就是说 再见了
So in other words, adios.